Amber Janzen Urban Planner

Profile

I aim to shape policies and initiatives that promote quality of life and place at the intersection of public health and urban planning. I will utilize my expertise to work with communities to develop a resilient and equitable food system in Marion County.

Education

Master of Urban and Regional Planning (MURP) Ball State University 2020

B.A. Applied Cultural Anthropology & Sustainability Ball State University 2011-2015

Contact



765-336-4791



aejanzen@gmail.com



Indianapolis, In

References

Jonathan Smith Senior Project Manager, HWC Engineering

Email: jlsmith4@gmail.com

Phone: 312-213-7131

Jim Walker Executive Director, Big Car Collaborative

Email: jim@bigcar.org Phone: 317-408-1366

Relevant Work Experience

Planner

HWC Engineering | Indianapolis, IN | August 2018-Present

I facilitate long range planning efforts and development strategies for Hoosier communities across Indiana. My primary responsibilities include demographic research, GIS analysis and mapping, and stakeholder and community engagement. I use this information to aid communities in the development, implementation, and adoption of planning policies, studies and strategies.

Planner and Programming Coordinator

Big Car Collaborative | Indianapolis, IN | May 2017- June 2018

I led placemaking and programming efforts to improve public spaces and build social cohesion. These efforts included public engagement and data reporting, program development, grant writing, and administrative support. I also helped to build and strengthen partnerships across the city to strengthen Big Car's mission and to enhance quality of life for Indianapolis residents.

Program Assistant

Ball State University | Muncie, Thailand, Nepal | August 2015-May 2017

I assisted in the development and execution of a nine-week study abroad program in Thailand and Nepal, led through the College of Architecture and Planning at Ball State. I marketed, recruited, prepared, and advised students before and promoted intercultural competency throughout the program.

Planning Intern

City of Carmel | Carmel, IN | May 2016- August 2016

I conducted a city-wide ADA assessment for Carmel's sidewalks and curb ramps. I also provided support in inventorying Carmel's trail system. Other duties included administrative support for the long-range and current planning staff.

Skills

Adobe Creative Suite
Mapping & Demographics
Wordpress
Microsoft Excel
Public and Stakeholder
Engagement
Strategic Planning
Project Management

Extra Curriculars

Board Member- Earth Charter Indiana, Indianapolis, IN Member- American Planning Association, Indiana Chapter Volunteer - Kheprw Institute, Indianapolis, Indianapolis, IN